Come out of there!
Phii Pong comes out at night
to hunt for its victims.
Once it catches its prey,
it kills them,
then rips open the belly,
and pulls out the guts,
and eats their organs.
DELUSION
If you see Phii Pong, then it must
kill you straight away.
Otherwise, it will die.
After it kills you,
then it starts to eat your guts.
Wouldn't it get diarrhea after that?
No. It's a ghost.
Ah…
But you said it turns into
a human in the morning.
They say that near your mother's village,
Phii Pongs are everywhere.
So, take care. You better watch yourself,
or you'll ger eaten.
- Wow.
- Oh look it's here!
- Look at that.
- Beautiful.
Say, Wan.
- Yeah?
- The food is delicious.
Did you order it from Bangkok?
Yote said you arranged it all.
Can I get their contact?
Of course you can, I'll text you.
Sunee is so lucky
to have you as her daughter-in-law.
So Wan, tell me, how are things with you?
I'm doing well.
You're so, you've been deputy, so long.
It's time you were school principal.
Excuse me, if you would.
Of course, dear.
Enough with the talking.
- Enough with that! Time to have fun now.
- A bit for everyone.
Okay, raise your glasses, to all of us.
To all of us! Here we go.
- Congratulations.
- Cheers.
Mrs. Wan, this delivery is for you.
I'll take care of it.
Our client ordered more, ma'am.
CASH SALE
FIVE CASES OF CHAMPAGNE, 39,000 BAHT
- Okay, you can take it in.
- Yes ma'am.
50TH ANNIVERSARY APPRECIATION BANQUET
KANG CHAI LIMITED PARTNERSHIP
SPONSORED BY LOEI FORWARD GROUP
- Cheers.
- Thank you so much.
I'd like to thank you all for today.
Thank you, cheers.
You can go home if you like.
Aim can stay with me.
You've been drinking.
I'm okay.
He can stay with me tonight.
You stay here.
My mom's expecting him to stay with us.
Transfer it, when you can.
That was my family's money anyway.
Just think of it,
as you helping out for a change.
Just this once.
I've given plenty of money to your family.
This is small change.
So, your grandparents had diarrhea?
No, because my grandparents
aren't Phii Pongs.
Stay long enough, and you'll find out.
Your grandparents will
be looking after you. Do you know why?
My mom says it's because
your parents are getting divorced.
Hey!
Hey! What are you kids playing?
Hey, what are you up to?
What's going on here?
We've got lychees. Come on, nice dessert.
- Oh! Yum!
- Let's go, good now.
Okay, lychee time!
MOM
Hello?
What's up, Mom?
Wan, you need to come
and talk to your dad.
I don't know what's wrong, but he's gone
a bit funny. He's got a machete!
What? Mom!
Mom!
Come out!
I said come on out!
Ma? Ma?
- Mom!
- Hey!
Ma?
Ma!
WAN
FOUR MISSED CALLS
50TH ANNIVERSARY APPRECIATION BANQUET
Aim.
Come on, we're going.
- You've gotta go?
- Okay, see you.
- Bye.
Goodbye, Aunt Wan.
What's up, Wan?
It's Dad, there's something wrong.
What? What's wrong?
Doctor, the patient is prepped.
Look, I'm with a patient right now.
Can you…Can you handle this?
For the moment.
You can sleep, we're not there yet.
Ma, I would have been all right alone.
I'm old enough now.
Yeah, but…
Who would keep me company? Hmm?
Grandpa's house is so boring.
There's never anything to do.
And it's hot, no AC.
No, it's not hot at all.
It's always cool there.
There are so many nice trees
and it's shady.
Trees aren't the same as AC
NASAO VILLAGE NASAO, CHIANG KHAN, LOEI
CHIANG KHAN POLICE STATION
POLICE MAJOR SASIDIT DESAYAKUL
INVESTIGATION DIVISION
CHIANG KHAN POLICE STATION
CAPT. BIRD: I HEARD YOU MOVED
TO CHIANG KHAN, PETE
I'M HERE WITH MY BOSS. LET'S MEET UP.
Hey, Uncle, are you going to
the village party this week?
I don't think so, not really my thing.
Huh?
It sounded like a lot of fun.
- There'll be lots of free beer.
- Mmm.
I'm bored. Feel like a smoke?
Okay, yeah, let's go.
Got a spare ticket.
If you want it.
Sure.
- Let's go.
- The missing person case, any updates?
The one the old lady came in to report.
Oh yeah, um, he…
Uh, he probably already showed up.
Probably just, got drunk or
passed out somewhere.
You know that for a fact, do you?
Uh…
The kid is 16, right?
Yeah, here sir.
The kid's name is Mued.
He's Grannie Paew's grandson.
And he's been missing
for over 24 hours now.
You know where they live?
Yeah.
Good.
Take me there,
I'll wait for you out front.
You said it.
- Yeah, so much for a smoke, eh?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- I'm coming, I'm coming.
Hey! What are you doing there?
You're Grandpa-Rong, are you?
Grannie Paew!
Are you there, Grannie Paew?
The police are here.
Oh! You take care now.
Careful, let me help you.
Have you found him?
They haven't yet.
This police officer is here
to help us look.
MUED
It's a scarecrow, keeps ghosts away.
They put that out,
if there's a male in the house.
Stops ghosts from taking them.
It's pretty common around here.
Grannie.
Where does the boy sleep?
Can I see please?
Come on in, Officer.
Where are your grandson's things?
He doesn't go to school?
He hasn't been to school
for over a year now.
Is there anything missing of value?
No, nothing.
Before he left,
he even left some money for me.
Where did he get that money from?
What do you see, Sergeant?
Tracks could be his.
- Tracks, inspector
- Check the kid's motorbike.
They don't remember the license plate.
Whatever you find out,
notify our patrol unit
and the other stations as well.
Sir.
Are the kids around here
in a local bike gang?
Where do they hang out?
I think they…
buy their booze at the local store
and then they go
- and drink it on the farms.
- Not in the forest?
No one would dare go
poking around in the forest, Officer.
There's Phii Pong there,
everyone's too afraid.
A ghost will catch you and eat you.
What ghost?
Phii Pong.
It hunts in the forest
for frogs and toads to eat.
Or it'll rip out your guts and eat them.
Tomorrow the shaman's going to perform
a ritual which will exorcise the ghost.
You should come along.
Everyone will be here.
Let me go! Let me go!
Where are you taking me?
Hey! What's going on there?
He's possessed again.
We'll take him to the shaman.
What's going on?
I want to go home.
He's a police officer,
he's here to help find the boy.
It took you long enough.
This is the ghost who's eaten him!
The boy went missing
after he was possessed.
Narong!
What did you do to my grandson?
Where did you take him to?
Uncle.
My name's Pete, I'm a new officer here.
Can you tell me whose blood
is that on your shirt?
He won't answer you, Officer.
He's Phii Pong.
You should just lock him up.
Just to be clear, you two didn't hurt him?
You didn't beat him up just
because you think he's Phii Pong.
That would be an offense.
It's my blood.
I was using a knife.
I cut myself.
He was trying to help me.
So he ran off to get assistance.
He didn't go for help.
He just ran into the forest.
Your husband's a ghost! He was hunting.
There are no ghosts here.
That's an amulet you're wearing, isn't it?
Ghosts can't be close to amulets,
can they?
You two live together, is that right?
Let's get you to a doctor, I'll drive you.
It's not a deep wound,
I'll be fine, thank you.
I'd like to help.
Let me drive you to the hospital now.
We'll get him checked out, too.
What's going on, Auntie?
It's your dad, he's been possessed.
Hospitals have germs, go wash your hands.
Okay.
I'm their daughter.
My name is Wan.
We're seeing to your mother's wound now.
- As for your father…
- His name is Narong.
Yes, the doctor on duty is assessing him.
I'll let you know when there's an update.
Good evening.
Are you their daughter?
Yes.
Wanrudee.
How long as your father been like this?
Not long.
But you don't live with them, do you?
So how can you be sure?
The neighbors say
he's been like this for a while now.
I visit them regularly.
I don't just leave them alone.
He was perfectly fine
the last time I saw him.
How long ago was that then?
A neurological condition could be serious.
I think that's for the doctor to decide.
I'm not sure that
you're qualified to know.
Am I wrong?
That's fair.
If you don't mind,
I'd like you to give this to your father.
There are things
I'd like to discuss with him…
Once the doctor
has finished his examination.
POLICE MAJOR SASIDIT DESAYAKUL
If my dad's done something illegal,
then please tell me.
As it stands,
no one has filed a complaint.
I do find your mother's wound
somewhat odd.
Speaking as a policeman.
Let me go! Let go!
Why did you bring me here?
- Let me go! Take your hands off me!
- Please calm down.
What medicine?
I'm not taking any medicine! I'm not sick!
You're all in on this together,
aren't you?
- You're trying to take my land off me!
- Please, sir!
- You're trying to take what's mine!
- We're trying to help you!
Based on my assessment of the patient,
he's beginning to show
the early signs of dementia.
Even his agitated behavior
and his constant talk of the past,
it seems he's become fixated
on these memories he has.
So…
How is this treated?
I should start
by telling you that there's
no treatment for this condition.
The medication I'm prescribing
will only help slow its progression,
so the symptoms don't worsen too quickly.
But frankly speaking,
your family needs to consider that
he will require constant care.
Indeed, in the future,
he may need 24 hour professional care.
I'll admit him for tonight and tomorrow.
You can take him home once he's awake.
EXAMINATION ROOM
YOTE
- Hello.
- Where did you take Aim?
I told you he was staying with me tonight.
Are you too stupid to understand that?
From now on, you need to tell me
before you take him anywhere, understand?
Are you listening to me? Wan!
Can you hear me? Hello?
Bit--
He has medicine to take after breakfast.
I'll leave it here for you.
Ma, let me clean that up,
you go get some sleep.
It's better if I do it.
So, Dad did that?
I don't know what it was he saw.
He tried to kill me. Who knows…
What it is that's wrong with him.
Perhaps it was a spirit?
Maybe something blew in and took over him.
Where's the machete?
I took it, and hid it.
How long has he been like this?
Ma.
The doctor said Dad is very sick.
It has nothing to do with any ghosts.
What would a doctor know?
I live with your father every day.
He wouldn't do that to me,
if he wasn't possessed.
You go to bed.
Is it time to charge that tablet?
What do you think?
Ma.
What's wrong with Grandpa?
Why was he shouting like that?
Grandpa's sick.
And we don't know what it is.
But, will he get better?
Mmm-mmm.
Mmm.
Ma…
Do you think that…
Phii Pong is a real thing?
It's silly.
It's all nonsense.
Well, some people say it's true.
Well, they're wrong.
They're all just silly stories, see.
Listen to me.
The people who say that,
they haven't actually seen anything.
- Right?
- Mmm.
They haven't.
Okay.
Yeah.
- Ma.
- Hmm?
Don't forget to brush your teeth.
I left the toothpaste out.
What's funny?
I think you're growing a moustache.
Hmm?
Yes, I can see it.
Look, it's so thick!
I think you need to shave!
I don't have a moustache!
I don't!
Stop it! stop it!
Oh, that tickles!
It tickles! Ah!
What did you forget? Hmm?
Good night! Have a sweet dream.
Thank you, Teacher Wan.
Good night.
- Night.
- You have sweet dreams.
Behold,
O gods and celestial beings.
You who abide in every tree
and mountain-wood,
in every deep forest and wilderness,
in all rivers, pools, and fish-bays.
Gather, all you hosts of deities.
My grandson.
Let the ghost free you, come back to me.
Get out! Gone! Be gone!
Gone! Be gone!
Be gone! Be gone!
Go! Get out!
- Get out!
- Be gone!
- Be gone! Get out!
FAMILY WAITING AREA
You still like liquid diabetes?
Don't joke around, Wat.
So, how long has he been in there?
A while now.
It's just a CT scan.
It shouldn't be too long.
How's Mom doing?
Her wound is healing.
Wat…if you're free…
You should go and see her.
Yeah, I will.
I swapped shifts.
If these drugs don't work.
I think we should seriously consider…
shifting him to a care center.
We can't take care of him on our own.
Let's see if the drugs work.
I don't want him abandoned.
For someone else to look after.
Can you manage alone?
I'll have to, won't I?
I've managed so far without you.
Pa.
Your father's condition has improved.
He should be fine.
But if any symptom return
once he's at home,
Please, feel free to contact us any time.
Thanks very much, I will.
I, proclaiming the four noble truths,
they obtained blessed victory
may these victories of the glorious dharma
and the sangha
be bestowed upon those who chant
and those who heal.
And now fill it up.
Beware of what the wind brings in.
We live close to the forest,
and to the mountains.
If you hear anything in the night,
do not heed it and do not say a word.
And keep your mind steady,
say your prayers before you retire.
Get out, get out!
Be gone! Get out! Come on!
- Get out!
- Be gone!
- Let's go!
Get out! Get out!
- Get out!
- Be gone!
Get out!
Open the gate, kid.
Get out! Be gone!
- Get out!
Do you live here?
Mmm-hmm.
There is a ghost here in your house.
- That's wrong.
- Your grandpa's a Phii Pong.
- Phii Pong! Be gone!
- Be gone! Get out!
- Get out!
- Go away!
- Be gone!
Sadhu. Sadhu. Sadhu.
Spirits of
the land, mountains, forests, and city.
If our children who became lost
in the forest or the town
have unintentionally offended you,
by body, mind, or speech,
I humbly ask for your forgiveness.
Please open the gates,
and show them the way,
and protect them
from harm, danger, or misfortune.
Open the way.
- Come on, let's go home.
- Yeah.
Aw, you caught me.
Uncle Wat!
Hi there Aim, what's up?
I came to see what this was all about.
Hmm.
They do some strange shit around here.
Not like in the city.
Did they scare you?
Come on, mosquitoes are biting.
- Okay.
- Yeah, let's go.
Where could it be?
Yes, that's right. Sit here.
Here.
Yay! Look, I got one! You go, Grandpa!
Uh…
That's it!
You're close.
Here.
Let me help.
Yeah!
There you go.
Caught 'em…
Yay! You did it, good one!
Great!
Grandpa, what's wrong?
Grandpa?
Grandpa, don't cry.
Go, you keep playing…
What time will you drop him?
He has taekwondo class tomorrow.
He'll be there in time for that.
I'm coming to get him now, so he can sleep
in and not have to wake up early.
Why do you want to do that?
He'll already be asleep by then.
I know what's best for my son.
I think you should consider that.
What the fuck are you trying to say, huh?
Wan--
Ma?
Ma!
Hey!
Grandpa! Grandpa!
Grandpa?
Grandpa!
Subtitle translation by: Parida Kim